The railway, the children... and the wonderful secret they'll share with you!
The Railway Children is a drama, family film directed by Lionel Jeffries.
At the dawn of the 20th century, following their father's arrest on suspicion of betraying state secrets, the three Waterbury children—Bobbie, Phyllis and
Peter—move with their mother to Yorkshire, where they find themselves involved in unexpected dramas along the railway by their new home.
Mrs. Waterbury, played by Dinah Sheridan.
Albert Perks, played by Bernard Cribbins.
Old Gentleman, played by William Mervyn.
Charles Waterbury, played by Iain Cuthbertson.
Roberta 'Bobbie' Waterbury, played by Jenny Agutter.
Phyllis Waterbury, played by Sally Thomsett.
The Railway Children is a 1970 British family drama film
based on the 1906 novel of the same name by E.
The film was directed by Lionel Jeffries and stars Dinah Sheridan, Jenny Agutter (who had earlier featured in the BBC's
1968 dramatisation of the novel), Sally Thomsett, Gary Warren and Bernard Cribbins in leading roles.
The film was released to cinemas in the United Kingdom on 21 December 1970.
The film rights were bought by Jeffries.
It was his directorial debut and he wrote the screenplay.
The Railway Children was a critical success, both at
time of release and in later years.
The film explores themes of northern england, countryside,
father, railway car, family relationships.
The tone is emotional.